Guide to the Gustave Jaeger Requardt papers, 1905-1966.
Requardt, Gustav Jaeger papers, 1905-1966.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gustav Jaeger Requardt papers, 1905-1966.
2548
Gustav Jaeger Requardt, 1886-1978.
1.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diary, reports, certificates, clippings, photographs, press releases.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Printed and photocopied items, mainly concerning Requardt's student years at Cornell University, his participation in alumni activities, his career in sanitary engineering, and his interest in national politics and public affairs.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Engineer.
Cornell University Class of 1909.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence; diary (1962) of Requardt's tour of Scandinavia, Holland, and West Germeny; reports; certificates; clippings; photographs; press releases; biographical sketches on the Requardt family; and printed and photocopied items, mainly concerning Requardt's student years at Cornell University, his participation in alumni activities, his career in sanitary engineering, and his interest in national politics and public affairs. Includes material relating to his partnership in Whitman, Requardt, and Associates (Baltimore, Maryland). Chief correspondents include John Marshall Butler, George H. Fallon, and Herbert R. O'Conor.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Requardt, Gustave Jaeger, 1886-1978.; Butler, John Marshall.; Fallon, George H.; O'Conor, Herbert R.; Requardt family.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University--Students.; Whitman, Requardt, and Associates.
Subjects:
Politics, Practical.; Civil engineering.; Sanitary engineering.; Voyages and travels.; Scandinavia--Description and travel.; West Germany--Description and travel.; Civil engineers.
Places:
Netherlands--Description and travel.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Cornell Undergraduate Correspondence, 1905-1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cornell Undergraduate Notes and Reports, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cornell Undergraduate Notes and Reports, 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cornell Undergraduate Miscellany, 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Diplomas and Certificates, 1909-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cornell Alumni Pamphlets, Notes and Correspondence, 1910-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Notes and Reports, Baltimore Civil Engineer, 1915-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Anti-New Deal Notes and Correspondence, 1936-1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Anti-Labor Movement Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Notes and Correspondence; Anti-Truman, Taft-Hartley Act, Cornell Engineering, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Notes and Correspondence; Industrial College of the Armed Forces, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Notes and Correspondence; Government Expenditures, Defeat of Democrats, Cornell Seal, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Notes and Correspondence; Japanese Treaty, Presidential Campaign, Seizure of WVBR, Tar Young, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Steel Strike, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Cornell Alumni Support, Inauguration of University of Maryland President, Amateur Track and Field, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Notes, Clippings, Correspondence; European Tour, Brick Metcalf 1901, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Notes, Clippings, Correspondence; Washington College Founders Day, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Notes, Clippings, Correspondence; Terrapin Recipes, Cornell Library Development, Cornell Law School Donation, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Notes, Clippings, Correspondence; Honoarary Membership A.S.C.E., Retirement of Deane Malott, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Notes, Clippings, Correspondence; Wages and Hours Act, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Continuous Reunion Club, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Notes, Correspondence, and Maps; Development of New Jersey Meadows, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Steel Strike and Inflation, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Labor Reform Bill, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Connally Reservation, Conservatism v. Liberalism, Secondary Boycotts, Capitol Punishment, Steel and Inflation, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Labor and Inflation, Forand Bill on Social Security, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence on Politics of Kennedy Administration, Berlin; Cuba; Farm Legislation; Federal Spending; Maritime Strike, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence on Politics of Kennedy Administration, Medical Care; Kennedy Administration; Minimun Wage Rates, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence on Politics of Kennedy Administration, Private Enterprise; Saturday Evening Post; Steel and Labor; Unions; Department of Urban Affairs; Use of Kennedy Name, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Arizona Trip, Water Pollution Act, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Tours of North Europe, Cornell University Council, Songs, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Fraternities, "The Successful Student," Civil Rights, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Goucher College, Civil Rights Bill, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Goldwater Campaign, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Requardt and Assoc., Cornell Centennial Campaign, Roland Park, Conservatism, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Correspondence and Manual of Cornell University Council, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Retirement, Cornell Quill and Dagger Society, Cornell Student Behavior, Fraternities at Cornell, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Notes, Correspondence, and Photos; Conservatism, American Youth, Fraternities at Cornell, Hydraulic Engineering, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence, and Photos; Student Behavior, Mississippi Trip, Tour of Europe, Liberals, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Photograph, G. Requardt, Age 80, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Nixon, Agnew, Campus Violence, Daniel Berrigan, Chi Psi Fire, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Civil Engineering Reports, Artciles, and Pamphlets, 1943-1967 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Daniel Berrigan, University Admissions Quotas, Conservatism, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Vietnam War, Cornell Alumni News, Nixon Economic Policy, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Teaching at Cornell, Cranch Report, Political Predictions, Defense of Nixon, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photographs, Miscellany, Nixon, Agnew Inauguration, Ford Family, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Agnew Registration, Cornell Policies, Nixon, J.F. Requardt 1972, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Vietnam Cease Fire, Clinton House (Ithaca), A.D. White House, Professional Engineering in Maryland, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Illegalities in Professional Engineering, Cornell Class of 1909, Private Enterprise, Baltimore City College Class of 1905, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Reunion 1974, U.S. Senator George Radcliffe (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Nixon, Baltimore Subway, Baltimore, Robert Moses, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Cornell Track, 88th Birthday, Greater Baltimore Committee, Willard Day, 1974 in Review (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Clippings, Robert Moses, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Private Enterprise, Roland Park, Cornell Council, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; George Meany, Baltimore City College Class of 1905, Cornell Financial Status, Davis Bacon Act, Vietnam, Consumer Protection Agency, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; A.S.C.E., John Walker, Double Taxation, Austin Kiplinger, "Brud" Holland, Common Situs Bill, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Black Students, Common Situs Bill, Unemployment Compensation, Free Enterprise, Water Pollution Legislation, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; "Case for Cornell" and Reaction to It, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Atrocities on Cornell Campus, Cornell Class of 1907, Alumni Concern for Cornell, Baltimore City College, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Presidential Campaign, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; New Cornell President, Cornell Judicial System, Autobiographical Sketch, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Cornell President Rhodes, Affirmative Action, Pete Weigle 1917, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Notes and Correspondence; Independence of Hillside College, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Consumer Protection Bill, Common Situs Bill of 1977, "Case for Cornell," Willard Straight Take Over Anniversary (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence; Nelson Levings, Deane Malott, Dale Corson, Jesse Helms, H.E.W., Illiteracy at Cornell, Tower Club, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Genealogy of Requardt Family in Maryland, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)